<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Educate</title>
    <description>Educate from Infozy provides latest News, Articles, Editorials etc for Ca Students.</description>
    <link>https://educate.infozy.tk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://educate.infozy.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 17:39:55 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 17:39:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stricter CSR Laws as per revised Companies Act</title>
        <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The Parliament has passed amendments to Companies Act and the bill now advocates for stricter laws for CSR.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Amendments are made to Section 135 to carry forward the unspent corporate social responsibility amount, to a special account to be spent within three financial years and transfer thereafter to the Fund specified in Schedule VII, such as PM&amp;#39;s National Relief Fund and the violation of the CSR rules could land company officials in jail for up to 3 years. Companies violating the rules will face a penalty of Rs 50,000 to Rs 25 lakh. Details are as below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In case the unspent amount does not relate to any ongoing project, unspent amounts to be transferred to a Fund specified under Schedule VII within a period of six months of the expiry of the financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;(ii) In case the unspent amount relates to any ongoing project subject to fulfilling of prescribed conditions, unspent amounts to be transferred by the company within a period of thirty days from the end of the financial year to a special account to be opened by the company in that behalf for that financial year in any scheduled bank to be called the Unspent Corporate Social Responsibility Account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;(iii) Such amount shall be spent by the company in pursuance of its obligation towards the Corporate Social Responsibility Policy within a period of three financial years from the date of such transfer, failing which, the company shall transfer the same to a Fund specified in Schedule VII, within a period of thirty days from the date of completion of the third financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;(iv) Penal provisions inserted as under:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The company - punishable with fine which shall not be less than Rs. 50,000 but which may extend to Rs. 25 lakh&lt;br /&gt;
Every officer of such company who is in default - shall be punishable with imprisonment for a term which may extend to 3 years or with fine which shall not be less than Rs. 50,000 but which may extend to Rs. 5 lakh, or with both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;(v) MCA empowered to give general or special directions to a company or class of companies as it considers necessary to ensure compliance of provisions of this section.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 21:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://educate.infozy.tk/stricter-csr-laws-as-per-revised-companies-act/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://educate.infozy.tk/stricter-csr-laws-as-per-revised-companies-act/</guid>
        
        <category>corporate</category>
        
        <category>students</category>
        
        
        <category>Corporate</category>
        
        <category>Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
